Register of the Milton Genecin papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Printed Matter, 1906-1987; 41-48 (Box 41-48: 9)
  - Pamphlets issued by the Socialist Workers Party or affiliated organizations or presses, 1930-1986 (Folder 42-45:)
    - Trotsky, Leon (Folder 43-44:)
      - Communism and Syndicalism; The Death Agony of Capitalism and the Tasks of the Fourth International; Europe and America; Fascism; The Kirov Assassination; I Stake My Life!; In Defense of the Russian Revolution; In Defense of the Soviet Union; Leon Sedoff (Folder 43: 11)
      - On Black Nationalism and Self-Determination; On Engels and Kautsky; On the Jewish Question; On the Paris Commune; On the Trade Unions; The Only Road for Germany; Problems of the Development of the U.S.S.R. (Folder 44: 1)
      - Soviet Economy in Danger; The Soviet Union and the Fourth International; The Spanish Revolution in Danger!; The Strategy of the World Revolution; The Turn in the Communist International and the German Situation; Stalinism and Bolshevism; Women and the Family; World Unemployment and the Five Year Plan (Folder 44: 2)
    - Vidal, Mirta. Chicanas Speak Out; Chicano Liberation and Revolutionary Youth (Folder 44: 3)
    - Michael Banda, The Chinese Communist Party and the Hungarian Revolution; Hugo Blanco, On Chile and Peru; William E. Bohannan, A Letter to American Negroes; Douglas Bravo, Douglas Bravo Speaks; Tom Cagle, Life in an Auto Plant; George Clarke, Build a Labor Party Now; Bert Corona, Bert Corona Speaks; Joyce Cowley, Pioneers of Women's Liberation; Charles Curtiss (C. Charles), Your Standard of Living (Folder 44: 4)
    - John Dewey, Truth Is On the March; Farrell Dobbs, Trade Union Problems; Theodore Edwards, Marxism and Christianity; Gerry Foley, Ireland in Rebellion; Beatrice Hansen, A Political Biography of Walter Reuther; C. L. R. James (J. R. Johnson), Why Negroes Should Oppose the War; Doug Jenness, Lenin as Election Campaign Manager; Linda Jenness, Socialism and Democracy; Joe Johnson, The Prison Revolt; Caroline Lund, The Family; Rosa Luxemburg, Reform or Revolution (Folder 44: 5)
    - Ronald Reosti, The Pollution Crisis; Harry Ring, Cuba and Problems of Workers' Democracy; Della Rossa, Why Watts Exploded; Jean Simon, Desegregation!; Max Shachtman, Ten Years; Herbert Solow, Union-Smashing in Sacramento; Betsey Stone, Sisterhood Is Powerful; Arne Swabeck, Unemployment and the American Working Class (Folder 44: 6)
    - Tony Thomas, In Defense of Black Nationalism; Robert Vernon, The Black Ghetto; Mary-Alice Waters, The Politics of Women's Liberation Today; Debby Woodroofe, Sisters in Struggle, 1848-1920; Malcolm X, Two Speeches; Arthur Young, Quebec Nationalism; Fred Zeller, The Road for Revolutionary Socialists (Folder 44: 7)
    - By multiple authors or no individual authors (Folder 44-45:)
      - Abortion; Attica; Behind China's "Great Cultural Revolution"; A Bill of Rights for Working People; Black Liberation and Political Power; Black Power in the Caribbean; Black Women's Liberation; The Death Agony of Capitalism and the Tasks of the Fourth International; Declaration of Principles and Constitution of the Socialist Workers Party; Documents of the Chicano Struggle; Documents of the Palestinian Resistance Movement (Folder 44: 8)
      - The Farmer-Labor Party; Fight the Slave Labor Law!; For Independent Politics and a Fighting Program; The Founding Conference of the Fourth International; Healy "Reconstructs" the Fourth International; In Defense of the Women's Movement; An Introduction to the Young Socialist Alliance (Folder 44: 9)
      - Join the Young Socialist Alliance; Kate Millett's Sexual Politics; La Raza!; La Raza Unida Party in Texas; A List of Publications on Socialism and the Labor Movement; Manifesto of the Fourth International on the Imperialist War and the Proletarian Revolution; May 1970; 1952 Election Platform, Socialist Workers Party; 1979 World Congress of the Fourth International (Folder 45: 1)
      - Revolution in Hungary and the Crisis of Stalinism; Revolutionary Strategy in the Fight against the Vietnam War; The Second Declaration of Havana; The Struggle for Chicano Liberation (Folder 45: 2)
      - Teachers and the War; To the Workers and Peasants of India; Today's Fight against the Bosses; A Transitional Program for Black Liberation; The Truth about Israel and Zionism; Two Views on Pan-Africanism; The United States and the Second World War; The Voice of Socialism; Vote for Socialism in 1956 (Folder 45: 3)
      - War and the Fourth International; The War in Vietnam; Watts and Harlem; Why We Are in Prison; Witch Hunt in Minnesota; Women and the Equal Rights Amendment; The Worldwide Youth Radicalization (Folder 45: 4)
  - Pamphlets issued by unaffiliated organizations or presses, 1906-1987 (Folder 45-48:)
    - Asia and Pacific region. Marie M. Keesing, Pacific Islands in War and Peace; Korea: We Accuse!; Catherine Porter, Filipinos and Their Country; Henry A. Wallace, Our Job in the Pacific (Folder 45: 5)
    - Charles H. Kerr and Company publications. Paul Lafargue, The Right to Be Lazy; Wilhelm Liebknecht, No Compromise; Jack London, The Apostate; Anton Pannekoek, Marxism and Darwinism; A. M. Simons, Class Struggle in America (Folder 45: 6)
    - China and Chinese publications. Isaac Deutcher, On the Chinese "Cultural Revolution"; Raise Higher the Revolutionary Banner of Marxism-Leninism; Self-Reliance and Independent National Economic Construction; Two Different Lines on the Question of War and Peace; Wang Ming, Revolutionary China Today; V. G. Wilcox, Out to the People, On to the Offensive against Monopoly (Folder 45: 7)
    - Civil liberties. Hugo Black, We Dissent; Anne Braden, House Un-American Activities Committee: Bulwark of Segregation; In the Shadow of Fear; Truman Nelson, People with Strength; Wesley Robert Wells, My Name Is Wesley Robert Wells (Folder 45: 8)
    - Communist Party publications (Folder 45-46:)
      - Earl Browder, Civil War in Nationalist China; Eugene Dennis, America at the Crossroads; Georgi Dimitrov, The War and the Working Class and Working Class Unity, Bulwark against Fascism; William Z. Foster, The Strike Situation; The Fourth National Convention of the Workers (Communist) Party of America; Ireland's Path to Freedom; Japanese Imperialism Exposed; Al Lannon, The Maritime Workers and the Imperialist War; V. I. Lenin, The Teachings of Karl Marx; Leninism or Trotskyism (Folder 45: 9)
      - A. B. Magil, The Real Father Coughlin; D. Z. Manuilsky, The Revolutionary Crisis Is Maturing; V. M. Molotov, The Meaning of the Soviet-German Non-Aggression Pact; Sean Murray, Ireland's Fight for Freedom and the Irish in the U.S.A.; New Program of the Communist Party U.S.A.; M. J. Olgin, Why Communism?; The People's Front in France; Wilhelm Pieck, We Are Fighting for a Soviet Germany; Program of the Communist International; Program of the Trade Union Educational League (Folder 46: 1)
      - Harry Raymond, Dixie Comes to New York; Joseph Stalin, Foundations of Leninism; The Struggle against Imperialist War and the Tasks of the Communists; A. Y. Vyshinsky, Trotskyism; Wang Ming, The Revolutionary Movement in the Colonial Countries; E. Yarovslavsky, The Meaning of the Soviet Trials (Folder 46: 2)
    - Cuba. Fidel Castro, Addresses Congress of American Women, May Day Speech, and On Vietnam; Cuba versus CIA; The Declaration of Havana; Theodore Draper, Cuba and United States Policy; Arthur Pincus, Terror in Cuba (Folder 46: 3)
    - India. Miriam S. Farley, Speaking of India; India and the European War; India Lodge Annual Report and Statement of Accounts for 1939; Indian National Congress Presidential Address and Resolution; L. W. Matters, India; Stanley Plastrik (Henry Judd), India in Revolt; B. J. Vaswani, India Explained (Folder 46: 4)
    - Labor. James Boggs, Pages from a Negro Worker's Notebook; Paul Jacobs, Old Before Its Time: Collective Bargaining at 28; John L. Lewis, Speech in Opposition to Taft-Hartley Statute; Robert Lynd, You Can Do It Better Democratically (Folder 46: 5)
    - Socialist Party publications. James Casey, The Crisis in the Communist Party; Draft for a Program for the Socialist Party of the United States; Harold J. Laski, Karl Marx; Rosa Luxemburg, Reform or Revolution; Out of Their Own Mouths: A Documentary Study of the New Line of the Comintern on War; M. Philips Price, The Soviet, the Terror and Intervention; Joel Seidman, Sit-Down; Gus Tyler, Youth Fights War!; Youth Want Jobs (Folder 46: 6)
    - Socialist publications (other organizations). Daniel De Leon, What Means This Strike? (Socialist Labor Party); Third Camp (Independent Socialist Committee); Toward an American Revolutionary Labor Movement (American Workers Party) (Folder 46: 7)
    - Soviet publications. Nikita Khrushchev, Report of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union to the 20th Party Congress; Resolutions of the 20th Congress of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union; Why War Was Not Prevented (Folder 47: 1)
    - Trotsky, Leon, writings published by non-SWP presses. Against Social-Patriotism; The Class Nature of the Soviet State; Culture and Socialism; From October to Brest-Litovsk; The Lesson of Spain; Marxism in the United States; 1905: Before and After; 1905: Results and Perspectives; The October Revolution; Perspectives of World Development; The Russian Revolution; What Hitler Wants; What Is an Insurrection?; Whither Europe? (Folder 47: 2)
    - Trotskyist publications (U.S. non-SWP). Carl Finamore, A Mass Action Strategy for Peace, Jobs and Justice (Socialist Action); Revolt in South Africa (Socialist Action); Arne Swabeck, Visiting Trotsky at Prinkipo; Myra Tanner Weiss, The Bustelo Incident (Folder 47: 3)
    - Trotskyist publications (non-U.S.). Against Wall Street and the Kremlin; Colvin R. de Silva, The Failure of Communalist Politics and Left Disunity; Leslie Goonawardene, What We Stand For; Ted Grant, A Socialist Policy for Labour; Abu Hashim, Egypt: A People Rising; Ernest Mandel (Ernest Germain), Marxism vs. Ultraleftism; The Moscow-Peking Dispute and the Fourth International; Michel Raptis (Michel Pablo), Capitalism or Socialism?; Andrew Scott, Does Russia's Entry Alter Britain's War?; The 20th Congress (C.P.S.U.) and World Trotskyism (Folder 47: 4)
    - Vietnam. Hugh Deane, The War in Vietnam; Caroline Jenness, Immediate Withdrawal vs. Negotiations?; Ramparts Vietnam Primer; Robert Scheer, How the United States Got Involved in Vietnam (Folder 47: 5)
    - Workers Age Publishers publications. Jay Lovestone, People's Front Illusion; Rosa Luxemburg, The Russian Revolution; Bertram D. Wolfe, Civil War in Spain (Folder 47: 6)
    - Yugoslavia (Folder 48:)
      - Bebler, Ales, Speech; Vlajko Begovic, Two and a Half Years of the Five-Year Plan; Milovan Djilas, Lenin on Relations between Socialist States and On New Roads of Socialism; FPR Yugoslavia; For the Defense of Peace; Edvard Kardelj, The Communist Party of Yugoslavia in the Struggle for New Yugoslavia, for People's Authority and for Socialism and On People's Democracy in Yugoslavia (Folder 48: 1)
      - Mosha Piyade, About the Legend that the Yugoslav Uprising Owed Its Existence to Soviet Assistance; Milentije Popovic, On Economic Relations among Socialist States; Kocha Popovich, On the Question of the Liberation War in Yugoslavia; Josip Broz Tito, Political Report of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of Yugoslavia; Veljko Vlahovic, Six Years of the People's State; Yugoslavia: New Land in the Making (Folder 48: 2)
    - Miscellaneous. Berkman, Alexander, The Kronstadt Rebellion; Albert Einstein, Why Socialism?; Peter Fryer, Hungary and the Communist Party; Emma Goldman, The Traffic in Women; In the Shadow of Dallas; A Lead to World Socialism; Julius Martov, The State and the Socialist Revolution; I. B. Tabata, The Freedom Struggle in South Africa; The Triple Revolution (Folder 48: 3)
  - Clippings (Folder 48: 4-5)
    - Articles from the Los Angeles Times re wage-price freeze, 1971-1972 (Folder 48: 4)
    - Articles from the Militant re labor solidarity days, 1975 and 1981 (Folder 48: 5)
  - Miscellany. Includes article re Vincent Dunne, and Carl Skoglund memento (Folder 48: 6)